Excuse me, sir. How did you get rich?
I sold my first company for $30 million.
I just sold my last one for
many, many, many, many hundreds of millions.
So you're rich rich?
Oh, I'm not rich. I'm wealthy.
Excuse me, sir. Is this your Rolls Royce?
This guy?
Yeah. How did you get Rolls
Royce rich, man? This is incredible.
I sold a television network to
News Corp for a lot of money.
For the $10 million?
For the $10 million.
I did the first Herbal Viagra. It was
the biggest seller GNC ever had at the time.
What was the biggest shit you ever had? What was
the most amount of money you made in a year?
About $17 million.
What did you do to
be able to get a Cullinan?
Oh, man. I'm an investor, man. I invest in education.
Education?
Absolutely.
What type of education?
Higher education. So I buy schools and
I own a higher ed institution, a college.
You go to college?
Yeah.
If you lost everything tomorrow,
could you make it all back?
Yeah. Yeah, no doubt. I would start an AI company.
AI is the greatest opportunity in our lifetime.
You're 62 today. If you die tomorrow, if you could give me one
more guiding principle to meet with the younger generation, what would that be?
Mark my words. This is about to be
one of the greatest videos that you've ever watched.
Guys, I just flew into Beverly Hills to meet up with an
interview with a nine-figure business legend and mogul, Robert Herjavec from Shark Tank.
Guys, he is one of the
wealthiest people in Los Angeles right now.
And I'm going to be getting the secrets from him on how he
built his empire, became wealthy, and how you can do the exact same thing.
I'm getting the exact secrets he
took to get rich in today's world.
So stay tuned from start to finish.
With that being said, let's
get this video on the way.
All right, so guys, we're going to
be meeting up with Robert very shortly.
But before we do that, guys, since we're in Beverly Hills, one of
the wealthiest zip codes in not just the United States, but the entire world,
we're going to go ask some of the people
that are out here what they did to become wealthy.
And I'm going to be going up to people in Rolls Royces and some of the craziest
cars to figure out how they got rich and how you can do the exact same thing.
Come on.
Hey, how about this guy right here? Are we
going to get him real quick? Should we try him?
That's my dad. You should.
Are you for real? All right,
come on. Let's go. Let's get it.
Hey, if he doesn't want to do it,
you got to get him to do it, okay?
I'm totally well.
Hey, sir.
How did you get rich?
Oh, man, not rich.
Yeah? What kind of business are you in?
I'm in the fitness and
health and wellness and sports business.
What do you do?
I'm Jake, body by Jake.
Jake, James. Nice to meet you, sir.
All right, man. Good to meet you.
Real quick.
Big fan of yours, man.
Can I interview you for a minute real quick?
Sure, go ahead.
So are you a business owner?
I sure am.
Well, how long have you been an entrepreneur?
I've been an entrepreneur since I'm 18 years old.
How old are you now?
You know, I'm 67 now.
You're not 67.
Yes, I am.
It's a smooth talker.
Come on, let's see the biceps.
They're there, but not there yet, though.
Come on.
It's safe to say, though, money stays in shape.
It definitely does.
It does.
But you know what, though?
Health is wealth.
It really is.
Do you think a lot of entrepreneurs neglect their health?
I think, look, the most important
thing in life is about taking shots.
It really is.
Do you take a lot of risks?
My whole career.
And the most important thing is you have to
have a partner who's with you all the way.
And my wife has stood with me since the
day we got married, and that's the most important thing.
When you first met her, when you were dating her early
on, how did you know that that was your life partner?
What did you see?
You just know, man.
You know what?
You just know.
You really do.
It's like the first house I bought.
You walk in, and you go, this is my house.
I've lived my life on
emotion, and you never look back.
Because as an entrepreneur, you win
a bunch, you lose a bunch.
And I've been blessed to win
a little bit more than I've lost.
But the most important thing is, at the end of the day, you
don't want to wake up when you're 60 or 70 or 80 years old
and look in the mirror and say,
you know, at 20, I had this idea.
At 30, I had an idea.
And you didn't do it.
Because that's the kind of stuff that makes you crazy.
I always say that the
most valuable piece of real estate,
is in graveyards, because there's billion-dollar ideas in
the ground of people that never took action.
I'll give you one last thing.
No is halfway to yes.
God bless.
I need a couple more with you real quick.
What was the most amount of
money you made in a year?
Oh, man.
I sold a television network to News Corp
for a lot of money called Fit TV.
Give me a range.
How much was it?
Put it this way.
A whole lot more than my allowance
was when I was 12 years old.
More than $10 million?
More than $100 million?
So real quick, real quick, real quick.
Did you come from a rich family?
Listen, man.
I came from a really awesome middle-class family.
I was born in Brooklyn, raised in Baldwin Strong.
I was born on an island, and I've been
very blessed to be able to pass it on now,
to teach my kids.
I have four kids, and it's Father's Day.
I'm going to go back and hang
out with my wife and my kids.
Your son's right here.
Let me ask you this.
You're 67.
Let's say me and you die tomorrow,
but you could leave one
more guiding principle to your son
to become successful like yourself and
become the best version of himself.
What's that last guiding principle
you would give to your son?
I'll give you this, brother.
My house burned down in the Palisades fire, okay?
And you think in life, especially here on Rodeo Drive,
that we're all defined by material
things, and that's not the case.
It's really not.
What are you made of?
And that's the question I'm going to
leave you with and everybody who watches you
because you talk a lot about making dough.
But more importantly is, what are you made of?
And that's it.
And one more for you.
Somebody trying to grow their business
and exit for more than $10 million.
Your best answer?
Don't take no for an answer, man.
Believe in yourself.
Did you have people that doubted you?
Every single day, man.
I was an overweight kid with a bad stutter.
My dad bought me a set of weights at 13.
I love when people say no.
As I said, no is halfway to yes.
Take that to the bank.
You got amazing advice, my friend.
Thank you so much, man.
Have a great day, man.
I appreciate it.
Hey, hey.
He just killed that shit, man.
If he has a handle, DM me
and that way I can tag him, bro.
I watch you all the time.
Thank you, brother.
Absolutely, bro.
Hey, that was just an incredible interview, man.
Beverly Hills is going crazy.
We got to go get this next one, you guys.
Come on.
Looks like he's pulling up on
a Rolls Royce Cullinan to the valet.
So we're going to go up and
try to get this interview for you guys.
Come on.
Excuse me, sir.
Sir.
Is this your Rolls Royce?
Yeah.
You got to get an
interview for one minute real quick.
Is that cool?
Yeah, why not, man?
What's up?
Is that all right?
I got the biggest business media channel.
I'll show you real quick.
We do stuff with like Shaq.
We just did a...
Oh, man, that's cool.
A bunch of people.
So what did you do to
be able to get a Cullinan?
Oh, man, I'm an investor, man.
I invest in education.
Education?
Absolutely.
What type of education?
Higher education.
So I buy schools and I own a higher
ed institution, a college that specializes in early education,
man.
You go to college?
Yeah.
Where?
What's the name of it?
Carlsbad, man.
It's Theoria Technical College.
We're out of Carlsbad, California.
So buying universities, is that like a
profitable business model to buy in today's world?
If you love what you do, yeah.
And that's what I do.
So I found a way to mirror my passion
and make a little money as doing it too.
So, man, I love what I do.
So you're an investor.
What's the number one thing that you look
for in either a founder or a company when
you're deciding to make that investment?
It's three things, really.
It's either people, processes, or profitability.
Most companies have two out of three.
If I can have value, then you get me.
If not, then I'll try to help you as much
as I can so you can push your own agenda.
Did you come from a lot of money?
No, man.
I come from nothing.
I come from humble beginnings.
What was the most amount of
money you've made in a single year?
About $17 million.
$17 million?
What happened that year?
Honestly?
Actually, the world crashed, right?
Pandemic.
This is 2020.
Yeah, and we just doubled down.
And for all my friends and companies that I
was investing in at the time, I didn't even
own.
But I just showed them how to make
themselves better and take opportunity and make some
money going.
So when everybody's fearful, that's when you're
like, this is the time to jump in.
Absolutely.
Have you met a lot of billionaires?
I have, man.
A lot of people make a
lot more money than me, man.
What have you learned from those people?
You don't have to be
the smartest person in the room.
Obama used to have something we call Obama effect, right?
Obama always surrounded himself by all the
smartest people around to make an educated
decision.
Right.
He was never the smartest man in the room.
Very likable, though.
He got those right people around him, though.
Yeah.
That was the thing.
So if you take that model of saying, okay,
man, I'm going to put all y'all together and
I'm going to speak last, that
way you always get your agenda across.
Right.
And everybody feels opinionated.
Everybody actually has a voice.
And everybody feels like they're contributing.
Do you have anybody that doubted
you when you were coming up?
Every last one of them.
Everybody said, hey, man, you can't do that.
You can own a school.
What?
Nobody does that.
But what people don't understand behind
every university, every college per se, there's
somebody who owned it at one point.
There's no board.
You know, it's always an individual.
Somebody had a dream.
So you didn't give a
fuck about what anybody else thought.
That's actually true.
I mean, I tried to stay within
the lanes, but I had to do what?
And my team that I had
with me, you know, believed in me.
And that's really the biggest thing.
Was there a conversation you had when somebody
really doubted you or went against you that
you were surprised about?
Yeah.
My own family.
You think your family would be the
biggest supporter, but there's always naysayers in
everywhere you go.
And I had to be able to be strong
enough to understand that not everybody's going to see
my vision.
It'd be the ones you love.
Always.
But today, they're my biggest fans.
You got amazing advice, my friend.
I mean.
Thank you for your time.
Absolutely.
Can I get your number?
Is that cool?
You can get my number.
Okay.
I got you.
Guys, Beverly Hills has been insane.
We're headed to go interview the legend
Robert Herjavec from Shark Tank very soon.
But listen, a billionaire once told me
that a deal doesn't exist unless it's signed.
And you'd be shocked how many entrepreneurs
end up losing deals because their signing
process is all types and messed up and outdated.
But that's why I use Odoo.
Odoo's signature apps let you customize,
send, and sign documents online fast.
You can add multiple signers, drag
and drop signature fields, and set the
signature to your own.
You can add a signing order in seconds.
It works on any device, and every step
is tracked and legally compliant in over 100
countries, including the US and Europe.
You can even store everything
in one place with unlimited storage.
And send auto reminders so
no one forgets about the deal.
And you want to know the best part?
Guys, it's completely free for life with your first app.
So if you're serious about business and
closing deals, then try Odoo today for free.
All you have to do is go down and
click the link in the description of this video.
With that being said, let's go get this next interview.
Excuse me, sir.
Is this your Rolls Royce?
Yes.
This guy.
Yeah.
What's your name again?
James, man.
The School of Hard Knocks, man.
James, I love your show.
Thank you, man.
You're from Austin, right?
Yes, sir.
Austin, Texas.
Down there with the Longhorns.
My man.
How did you get Rolls Royce rich, man?
This is incredible.
Oh, we're just lucky.
We're lucky people.
So you believe in luck.
A lot of successful people become lucky.
Yeah, we're crazy hard workers.
What line of business were you in?
We're promoters.
We got in the health business a long time ago.
I did the first herbal Viagra.
It was the biggest seller
GNC ever had at the time.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
That was in, what, 98?
So we've been doing a lot of stuff.
We're in the telemedicine business now, but
I'm not doing as good as you.
I love watching your show.
I saw you talking to Tom Cruise.
That's my guy.
Yes, sir.
There's so many guys out there.
But I want to learn from you real quick.
Somebody's trying to find a winning
product in whatever industry they're in.
What advice would you give to them?
You found a product that was able to
generate you tens, hundreds of millions of dollars
throughout your career.
How can somebody find a winning product in today's world?
Hey, just keep your eyes open.
Read a lot.
Talk to people.
Network.
But just read a lot.
Think a lot.
So you've got a lot of books?
A gazillion books.
Any entrepreneur to read.
Think and grow rich.
And, of course, Dan Kennedy's Ultimate Sales Letter.
I remember I read that
in a hotel bathroom one night.
Changed your life?
Yeah, it was a great one.
This is my genius wife.
What you really need to do is find
a beautiful French girl that can do anything
and listen to all your
nonsense, and you're good to go.
What was the biggest issue you ever had?
What was the most amount of
money you made in a year?
Hundreds of millions of dollars.
Did you have anybody that doubted you early on?
Yeah, sure.
Everybody, of course.
Trust me.
We're in Beverly Hills.
There's all these little wise
guys around that were killing me.
You know?
Yeah, just killing us.
But, yeah, you just keep your head down.
You keep moving forward.
Hey, we'll see.
Were you ever afraid of going to a competitive market?
No, not at all.
Why not?
The more competitive something is, that
means there's an opportunity to do stuff.
Yeah, you want to go to something where everybody's selling.
It's like if you're going to put a gas station, the best
place to put a gas station is next to another gas station.
So talk to me about it.
You see a competitive market.
How do you go in and stand out?
What's your unique selling angle?
What's your unique selling proposition?
When we came out with Herbal
Viagra, it was the first Herbal Viagra,
we did a prostate infomercial with Larry King,
and we found this crazy product
over in Europe that was like,
it's a very different way of processing herbs.
You've got to find something different.
There's a million guys selling the same nonsense.
You have to find something different.
So you're selling Viagra.
Look at this kid.
My goodness.
He's printing money, this kid.
What are you, like 17 years old, 18 years old?
There we go.
Same thing.
Young guy.
What's the difference?
How old are you?
You look great for 62.
Oh, thanks.
If you die tomorrow and you had
one more guiding principle to lead with me,
so that way I can become
successful like you at 62 years old.
Just keep doing what you're doing.
You're hustling.
It's a Sunday afternoon.
It's Father's Day.
And what are you doing?
You're not sleeping.
You're not resting.
You're out trying to make dough.
You're trying to make things happen.
You're snooping around.
This is probably a great place.
There's a little car show going on.
Go talk to those people.
No, keep hustling.
Keep your eyes open.
Keep thinking big.
Think big.
Just think big and never, ever, no matter what, quit.
Don't ever quit.
We've been punched in the head
so many times, it's not even funny.
You guys are doing great.
Appreciate you, man.
Good to meet you.
It's so funny.
I look at your stuff all the time.
I appreciate you.
It's very interesting.
You ask great questions.
Thank you.
I saw you had Will Smith the other
day and so many of these gazillionaire guys.
Thank you so much for your time.
I appreciate you, guys.
Guys, the time has come.
I'm headed right now to walk over and
interview the legend, the business mogul from Shark Tank,
Robert Herjavec, to figure out how he built
and sold his company for tens of millions
of dollars and how you can become rich,
real money rich, just like him in today's world
and the secrets that he took to become wealthy.
Let's go meet him and go
see what he has to say.
Come on.
Robert, how you doing?
Great to meet you.
Great.
It's great to meet you.
It's such a pleasure.
Likewise.
Happy to be out here.
Thanks for coming to meet us.
I really appreciate that.
Hey, man.
It's nice to meet you.
Did you call me sir?
What the fuck?
What was Tom Cruise like?
He was awesome.
He was super cool.
Here's the thing.
I got one rule.
Yeah.
No holding back.
I want you to give them
the secrets to become a wealthy.
Okay.
Can you make that happen?
Got it.
Who am I here with today?
Robert Herjavec from Shark Tank.
For those that don't know, what industry
did you decide to pursue a career in?
I'm one of the biggest people in
the world in cybersecurity and now AI.
But you've been in the business since like
1990 was when you started your first company.
I'm actually 95 years old,
but I work out a lot.
I look great.
No, I've been doing it for
a long time, since I was 21.
That was earlier in a time where there was
a lot of doubt about the internet, about the
future of cybersecurity.
What did you see early on that
made you want to pursue this business?
You can get rich by following a trend.
You can get wealthy by creating a trend.
So I got ahead of the cybersecurity internet world.
Did you come from a lot of money?
No, man.
We were like very melodramatic.
I came to Canada on a boat.
My parents crossed the border
in the middle of the night.
I mean, it was just
a classic rags through riches story.
So what was your turning point to financial freedom?
Great question.
Cuban and I had this conversation.
And Cuban said when he was 12
years old, he wanted to be rich.
When I was 12 years old,
I didn't want to be poor.
That was my motivation.
I think in life, you're either highly motivated,
and I wasn't, or really bad stuff happens
to you, and you got to make a decision.
Either you accept your life or you change.
Nothing changes if nothing changes.
Nothing changes unless you change.
I love that.
That's a bar right there.
If you're not willing to do something different
today, you're going to lead the life you had
yesterday.
That's fire right there.
So throughout your career, what was the most
amount of money you made in a single?
500 million.
But that included the sale
of a business and capital gains.
On income basis, I probably
18 million on an income basis.
But here's the key.
You can get very rich making income.
It's very hard to get wealthy making a big income.
You got to have capital gains.
You got to build something
of value that you can sell.
Have you ever been fucked over in business?
Oh my God.
My first company, I had
this lady who worked for me.
She quit and then she started crying.
And I'm like, oh my
gosh, I'm such a great boss.
She sat to lead.
She says to me on
the way out, your sales manager.
Has a company on the
side and he's stealing from you.
He's bringing one order in and then
putting another order into his own company.
He was literally stealing from me for a year.
I had no idea.
How do you deal with that when
you find a cancer in the company?
How did you address that at the moment?
Or maybe something you learned from that
if somebody is dealing with a similar circumstance
in their business that they're running.
Barbara told me this a long time ago.
People assume when you're successful
that you don't have bad days.
Barbara said this to me, the difference between
successful people and others is how long they
wallow in misery.
So what did I do?
I felt really sorry for myself.
I cried.
I mean, I swear to God, I cried.
I'm like, oh my God, I'm losing money.
And you know what I did five minutes later?
I said, fuck it.
I just got to get up
and I got to do it again.
It reminds me, Elon Musk says that entrepreneurship
is like eating glass and staring into the
abyss.
It's so true.
You know, Elon said to me one time, I said
to him, I heard a rumor that you're a micromanager
and he said, absolutely not true.
I'm not a micromanager.
I'm a nano manager.
As a multi nine figure entrepreneur, what
is the best financial advice you've ever received?
Maybe very contradictory because I'm not
a, I'm not a big investor.
I'm not a big investor in stocks and that.
I mean, I have a lot
of money in stocks, but real estate.
Charlie Munger said to me one time, if you
want to become rich in life, never sell a
house.
Always keep every house.
I've never lost money on real estate.
Do you have to have a lot of
money to start creating wealth in real estate?
No, you have to be able to hang onto it.
So if you can hang onto a property
for 10 years, for sure, you'll make money.
The problem is from liquidity, if you
have to sell it within 10 years.
You're a good salesman.
Oh, I'm a great salesman.
Give me your best sales advice right here.
You've been at the table with some very
heavy hitters, but you sold to massive companies.
Give me a quick sales masterclass.
Right here.
Before I teach you to sell,
tell me who I'm selling to.
Biggest mistake people make in sales is they
have a pitch and they applied that pitch to
every single person.
Before I open my mouth, before I tell you how
great my product or I am, I got to know
who you are.
I got to know your need.
Before you sell, find out the need.
What's more important in the business world,
what you know or who you know?
What you know.
Absolute bullshit.
When I started out in
business, my mom was a receptionist.
My dad swept floors in a factory.
Every person I knew in business
said this bullshit advice to me.
It's not what you know.
It's who you know.
In order to make money, you need money.
I was screwed.
I was 23 years old starting with nothing.
If you don't know anybody, you got to
become the person other people want to know.
Because successful people aren't just going
to go spend their time with somebody.
I always like to say that you want
to network with successful people to become successful.
You want to network when you provide something of value.
Build your own brand.
Other people will come to you.
Among yourself and the most highly successful people
that you study and know, what is that
one trait that they all have in common?
Obsession.
Absolutely.
It's easy.
Passion is easy, but all that stuff fades.
Obsession lasts.
I've never met somebody ultra successful
who doesn't absolutely love what they do.
They're a little crazy?
Oh yeah.
You got to be a little crazy.
You have to have the ability to see not the
way the world is, but you have to have the
ability to see the world for
what you want to make it.
And that's either obsession or you're just crazy.
Is it safe to say that
you've lost your mind a little bit?
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
I mean, that's why I work out so much.
I have to keep my sanity.
How old are you?
You don't look 62.
What's the secret to looking
this young at 62 years old?
They say money stays in shape
and you're living proof of it.
We're just talking about this today.
The biggest flex of wealth today is being in shape.
It's not a nice car.
It's not a new jet.
All those things are super cool.
It's staying in shape.
If you're not using your money
to stay healthy, what's the point?
How many companies have you invested in?
40, 50 through Shark Tank.
What is the best industry somebody should
be looking to get into in today's world?
It depends if you're starting with money
or if you're not starting with money.
If you're starting with money, you have to
use capital as a leverage, as a barrier to
entry to others.
So commercial buildings, data centers are really
big now, land, that kind of stuff.
If you have no money, e-commerce.
Why?
Well, because you don't need any money.
It's saturated.
They say it's saturated though, no?
You don't think so?
I don't think it is.
It depends on your brand.
I think it's easier to build a brand today online.
You invest in people or ideas?
People, always.
A great person can make a bad idea good.
A bad person can take a
great business and completely screw it up.
I love that.
I have to ask you.
One of the best pieces of content I've
ever seen on the internet is you talking about
beware of the man in the t-shirt.
I love that.
Oh, thank you.
Can you break that down for people
that may not have seen that before?
Mark Cuban was on our show.
This was his last year.
And when I first met him, I
love to dress well, love a good suit.
And I meet Mark, he's dressed
in a t-shirt like a slob.
I walk by his trailer and
literally he's got this $5,000 suit.
It's in a pile on the frigging ground.
And I'm like, dude, care a little.
He looks at me and
he says, I don't have to.
I didn't understand it at the time.
But later on, I realized you walk into a room
and there's 10 guys with a suit and one guy
in the back with a t-shirt.
Beware the man in the t-shirt because that guy
in the t-shirt worked his ass off to get
to a point that he or
she can wear whatever they want.
He doesn't have to dress to impress.
Mark is not selling people.
People are selling him.
If you lost everything tomorrow,
could you make it all back?
Yeah.
Yeah, no doubt.
What would you do?
Let's say you had to start from
zero, but you kept your contact book.
Oh, I would start an AI company.
AI is the greatest opportunity in our lifetime.
Yeah.
What part of AI?
All of it right now.
But the consumer element of
AI is going to go away.
I like the data infrastructure part of AI.
Are you using AI in all your businesses?
Yes, 100%.
My wife just wrote a movie script using AI.
Give me one hack that a
business owner can use to leverage AI.
Train your AI model to the way you work.
So we spent a lot of time training our version
of AI to write like me, and it now writes
better than I do.
My AI is more like Robert Herjavec than Robert Herjavec.
You're 62 today.
If you die tomorrow.
If you die, you're going to die.
I'm going to die.
You guys are crazy.
You're crazy.
I don't know if you could give me
one more guiding principle to lead with the younger
generation.
What would that be?
Sell joy.
Sell what?
You said joy?
Joy.
When I had nothing and I
didn't understand computers or cyber or anything.
I used to call on clients and
I filled their day with joy and happiness.
So whoever dealt with me always
remembered me as the nice, fun guy.
So emotion's an important component in business.
It's not what you say.
It's how you make people feel.
It's really true.
And so the less you have,
the nicer and the more engaging.
the more engaging you have to be. What's
the deepest life quote you've ever heard? A friend
of mine who's a priest said this to me
one time, you'll never find anything in life as fascinating
as another human being. And I'm deeply Christian. And
so I try to approach every human being that
way. Everybody has a story. Everybody has something
to tell. And if you go to them with
open fascination about their life, you'll learn them.
And that works in sales too. Faith has been
important for you? Faith's very important to me.
I love it. You got amazing advice, sir. Oh,
thank you so much for your time. I
really appreciate it. Guys, that's one of my favorite
interviews that I've ever done. I need you guys to
stop right now. I need you to like and subscribe
for amazing content that I've got coming every
week, going all over the world to interview the
wealthiest and the most successful people for you guys.
And if you are not a member yet, guys,
I give you direct access to the multimillionaires
and billionaires I interview every single week on
this channel, where you can ask your
questions directly to nine figure entrepreneurs, just like
Robert Herjavec. Imagine getting on a live call
with a guy like Robert and getting mentored by
him. Watch what would happen to your business,
your life. I guarantee you that it would double,
triple, maybe even 10%.
If you've got a room with a mentor like
that, and I give you that access every single week.
So go down to the link in the description
of this video to join the school of mentors,
the number one community for business owners. With that
being said, I'll see you in the next video.